Guide to the Annie Burr Lewis and Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Photographs
The Lewis Walpole Library
- Places, 1860–1978; Series V; 6.59; 7 boxes + 1 broadside + 1 roll
  - Europe
    - England, Norfolk: Felbrigg Hall, 1958, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Views of the exterior and library of Robert Wyndham Ketton-Cremer's home; the images include slides from the Lewises' 1955 visit.
    - England, Twickenham: Strawberry Hill, 1950, 1955, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
      For earlier and additional photographs of Strawberry Hill, particularly those relating to building repairs and restoration, see the St. Mary's College correspondence folder in Series I of the Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers (LWL MSS 20).
    - Other images, circa 1920-1961 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      In addition to prints, the folder holds color transparencies of the Lewises' 1951 trip to England, and slide sets of their 1954 trip to Italy, their 1955 visit to The Vyne, Lady Reading, Stokesay Castle, Syon House, Strawberry Hill, and Cambridge, and their 1957 trip to England and Scotland.
- Unsorted and Unidentified Images, 1900–1979; Series VI; 2.5; 6 boxes
  The series contains negatives, with some prints, which were found in their original commercial processing envelopes inscribed by Annie Lewis. They were arranged in groups by date or by subject. Filed at the end are images of unidentified people and places, including unidentified friends photographed at the Lewises' homes in Farmington and Newport. Any inscriptions made by Annie Lewis were transcribed as file titles, or appear in notes at the folder level.
  Series VI is organized into two subseries: By Date, and By Subject.
  - By Date
    - circa 1900 California (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1938 Newport (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1940 Farmington / Newport (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1941 Farmington / Washington (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1941 Summer (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1946 Winter Farmington & Newport (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1947 Australia (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1949 Garden St pix (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 1949 or 1950 Summer, 1949–1950 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 1949 or 1950 Yusha (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - 1950 Farmington spring (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - 1950 Farmington houses (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - 1950 Spring and Summer (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - 1950 Ore-boat William A Irvin, 1950 August (Box 14, Folder 14)
      The SS William A. Irvin was the flagship of the United States Steel Corporation's lake freighter fleet. In service on the Great Lakes from 1938 to 1978, she hauled iron ore from ports on Lake Superior to U.S. Steel mills on lakes Michigan and Erie. Guests of Irving Sands Olds (1887-1963), the chairman of U.S. Steel from 1940 to 1952, were able experience the same journey in the ship's luxurious passenger quarters. The folder holds color transparencies, negatives, and prints from a trip taken by the Lewises in August 1950. Prints from the Lewises' cruise with the Sherrills can be found in the album in Series II, Box 31.
    - 1951 Hugh & Polly McClure-Smith (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - 1951 Winter (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - 1951 Spring (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - 1951 Summer and Autumn (Box 14, Folder 18)
      Martha's Vineyard / S C Roberts / Farmington houses / Newport
    - 1951 Autumn (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      Old Houses / Christmas with Dodge girls / Lindsays / Achesons / Athertons
    - 1952 Newport (Box 14, Folder 21)
      Children's party / Hammersmith Players / Beach pix / Burr Nash & Ted / Stones / Coes / Athertons
    - 1952 Summer (Box 14, Folder 22)
      Newport and Conway Mass. [MacLeish home]
    - 1953 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      Newport / Walkers / Hammersmith / Ireland, Kerry & Cork / Achesons / Stones / Brayton /
    - 1953 & 1954 Burr Nash (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - 1954 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Children's party / Lee & Chas Stone / Hurricane / Friendship tour / Newport / Achesons & John Mason / Browns
    - 1954 Roberts (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1955 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Strawberry Hill / Manchester, Mass / Conway, Mass / Poodles / A. MacLeish / Miss Porter's / Reading Club
    - 1955 June England (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1956 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Newport / Bedford / Old Farmington Burial Ground / Dodges / Nashes / Athertons / Mount Vernon / Dogs
    - 1956 Summer (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - 1957 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      L-F Scholars / Conway, Mass.
    - 1958 Spring & Summer (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1958 Summer (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Walpole professors & wives
    - 1958 September Farmington (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - 1958 Caroline Kennedy (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - By Subject
    - California, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Dogs, circa 1930-1959 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Includes a set of slides formerly in a box Annie Lewis inscribed: "Puppies."
    - Poodle, circa 1950 (Box 33 (Oversize), Folder 9)
    - England, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Europe [?], undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Miss Porter's groups, 1958, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Includes color slides of various events at the school.
    - New York from the Queen Mary, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - North Africa, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - South Carolina, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Presumed to be photographs taken in and around Charleston; one negative shows the Fort Moultrie monument in White Point Garden.
    - Unidentified friends in Farmington, 1956, 1958, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Random photographs and negatives taken at the Lewises' home in Farmington; includes color transparencies.
    - Unidentified friends in Newport, 1956, 1961, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Random photographs and negatives taken at the Lewises' home in Newport; includes color transparencies.
    - Unidentified people, undated (Box 16, Folder 3-7)
      Includes formal studio portraits, group portraits, and snapshots of people.
    - Unidentified people, 1920, 1942, undated (Box 33 (Oversize), Folder 10)
    - Unidentified children, circa 1920-1963, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Photographs of children; many are likely to be nieces and nephews on the Auchincloss side of the family.
    - Unidentified children, undated (Box 33 (Oversize), Folder 11)
    - Unidentified places, undated (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
      Prints and transparencies of unidentified residences and landscapes. Most appear to be in the northeastern United States.
    - Unidentified places, undated (Box 33 (Oversize), Folder 12)
    - Unsorted negatives, circa 1910-1959 (Box 17, Folder 4-7)
      Sheet film negatives in their original enclosures without indication of date or subject.
    - Unsorted negatives, circa 1955 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Random strip film negatives without identification.
    - Unsorted negatives, 1913-circa 1930 (Box 18, Folder 1-6)
      Sheet film negatives in their original enclosures, most without indication of date or subject.
    - Unsorted negatives, circa 1956 (Box 19)
      Fourteen aluminum cannisters with exposed and developed strip film; they are unlabeled and undated.